Elias Dominguez Pires

Full Stack Developer

Asunción, Paraguay (GMT-4) (+595) 971 748967 elias.dominguezpires@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/eliasdominguezpires/ https://github.com/eliasdominguezpires

Engineer, Full Stack developer with 8+ years of experience, involved in the entire software development life cycle using Java EE, Node, React and Angular. I have experience in Backend and Frontend, mobile applications and server environments. I am proactive and enjoy teamwork. I have experience leading teams using agile methodologies. I am currently looking for remote positions that allow me to grow both personally and professionally.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance, Full Stack Developer — 2015 - actualmente

- Analysis, development and implementation for the process of generating digital invoices and electronic signatures.
- Streamlining and automation of citizen complaints through the design and development of a mobile application for the management, organization and display of information.
- Leader, design, analysis and development of a reusable system adaptable to any type of small and medium-sized business (Purchases Sales Stock Movements Cash registers Reports Customer file).

Stack: Google Api, Google Cloud, Java EE, Maven, MyBatis, Scrum, Click Up, WildFly, Linux, Angular 8+, Spring, Jira, Slack, Wildfly, Scrum, React Native, Redux, Navigate, Google Play Console, Cloud Binary, Node JS, TypeScript.

GV-CORP, Analista Desarrollador — Marzo, 2021 - actualmente

• Development of a Banking Core that allows bank employees to obtain information about lines of credit, loans, customers, accounting and reports.

Stack: Java EE, Cuba Platform, Jira, Apache, Scrum, Jenkins, Rancher.

MUV, Full Stack Developer — Junio 2019 - Julio 2020

• I increased the visibility of the company through the development of a portal that allows the administration of the company and the portfolio of corporate clients for a service platform such as Uber.

Stack: React JS, Material UI, Bootstrap, Git, Jira, Scrum

WarpCom, Full Stack Developer — Enero 2020 - Diciembre 2020

• Optimized the information registration process of the Mercedes and Audi dealership, through the development of a web application that allows organizing and viewing information on sales and customers.

Stack: CYPRESS, NX, Tailwind, RxJS, NgRx, Angular 8+, TDD, JIRA, SCRUM, ESLint, NPX, ng test, SonarQube.

Super Optical, Director Ejecutivo — septiembre 2019 - diciembre 2020

• Funding partner of a company dedicated to the import and distribution of ophthalmological frames with more than 45 clients in the region.

TDN - Kiga S.A, Full Stack Developer — 2018 - 2020

• Analyze and develop new requirements for the process and generation of digital invoices and electronic signatures.

Stack: Angular, Java EE, TDD, JIRA, SCRUM, Postgres, Spring, ng test, SonarQube.

Konecta, Full Stack Developer - Team Leader — 2013 - 2018

- Analysis and development of the migration of applications, existing processes and new requirements, optimizing flows and execution times.
- 20% time optimization in the creation of services for the restoration of lines through processed payments for a CRM telecommunications system.
- I performed the extraction, transformation and loading of an Oracle database to Postgres using Pentaho connected to two databases.
- I developed several modules of banking systems and an electronic ticketing system.
- System Fogapy, Analysis and development for a new accounting system.

Stack: Java EE, Angular, Docker, Git, Hibernate, Spring, Bootstrap, Material UI, SQL server, Maven, Oracle, Postgres, Spoon Pentaho Data Integration, MyBatis, Keycloak, Postgres, Grunt, AngularJS, Jira, Slack, SonarQube.

PROJECTS

Denuncias PY(Independiente) - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.py.dompir.denunciaspyapp - 2021

• Analyzed, designed and developed a mobile application for the management, speeding up and automatizing complaints of Paraguayan citizens. **Stack:** React Native, Google Cloud, Google Play, Node JS, Java EE.

Dompir (Independiente) - http://www.dompir.com/ - 2020

• I analyzed, designed and developed a reusable system adaptable to any type of small and medium-sized business. **Stack**: lava EE, Maven, Spring, Angular 8+, Google Cloud, Linux, Postgres, Docker.

Datos Abiertos (Konecta) - https://www.datos.gov.py/ - 2017

• I carried out the analysis, design and development of a Web system for the transparency of information in all the state entities of the PY. **Stack:** Java EE, Spring, Angular 8, Postgres, Docker.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Advanced: Java EE, JS, SQL, HTML, TypeScript; Intermediate: PLSQL, Groovy.

Frameworks Tools: <u>Advanced</u>: Angular (1.4) (7+), React Native, React JS, Spring Boot, Maven, MyBatis, Grunt, NPM; <u>Intermediate</u>: Tailwind, RxJS, TDD, Cypress Android Studio, Docker, Kubernetes ESLint, ng test, Spoon Pentaho Data Integration, WildFly, Apache, Nest.JS, Next.JS, Keycloak, OAuth2.0, SonarQube.

Data Base: Advanced: Oracle, Postgres, MySQL, SQL Server; Intermediate: NoSQL, Firebase, Mongo DB.

Tools: Git, Jira, Confluence, Slack, Google Cloud Platform, Google Play Console, Google Domains, Jenkins, Rancher, Microsoft Data Tools, Trello, Click Up, SourceTree, GitLab, FileZilla, Postman.

Agile: Scrum, Kanban, Project Management, mejora continua, calidad de software, planificación de pruebas.

Languages: Intermediate: inglés; Native: español, guaraní.

EDUCATION

Universidad Columbia del Paraguay - Asunción, Paraguay. IT Engineering, May 2016.

CERTIFICATES

React Native: Native Applications for IOS and Android - Udemy. 2022.

Redux in Angular - Udemy. 2021.

Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure - Coursera. 2021.

Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate (SFPC) - CertiProf. 2020.

Redux Course - Platzi. 2019.

React Navigation Course - Platzi. 2019.

React Native Course - Platzi. 2018.

Cisco Certified Network Associate CNNA - Cisco. 2012.